{
    "uid": "bb2d4b38-3f4f-4639-8b09-ef17bb229b33",
    "title": "tcpdump Challenge 1",
    "instructions": "<p>Now it's time to put your <b>tcpdump</b> and command-line analysis skills to the test!</p><p>The SOC received an alert that an endpoint was exhibiting abnormal behavior as it triggered several detections, pointing to a potential info-stealer malware variant. As a SOC Analyst at <i>Astley Financial</i>, review the <code>tcpdump_challenge.pcap</code> packet capture and analyze its contents to complete the report below.</p><h3>Challenge File:</h3><p><ul><li><code>02_Network_Security/01_tcpdump/Challenges/tcpdump_challenge.pcap</code></li></ul></p>",
  
  
    "questions": [
        {
            "quid": "077a7f1d",
            "question": "How many total packets are in the <code>tcpdump_challenge.pcap</code> packet capture?",
            "hint": "Read in the packet capture. The <code>--count</code> argument is your friend!",
            "type": "text_input",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["1344", "1344 packets"]  
        },
        {
            "quid": "9cbda42f",
            "question": "How many <b>ICMP</b> packets are in the challenge.pcap packet capture?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "Read in the packet capture. Filter the protocol. The <code>--count</code> argument is your friend!",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["132", "132 packets"]  
        },
        {
            "quid": "fea63286",
            "question": "What is the ASN of the destination IP address that the endpoint was pinging?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "First, filter the ICMP packets. The Autonomous System Number (ASN) of an IP address can usually be found by performing an IP lookup.",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["AS13335", "13335"]  
        },
        {
            "quid": "622b47b8",
            "question": "How many HTTP <b>POST</b> requests were made in the packet capture?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "First, read in the packet capture. Then, consider using a pattern matching command to search for the word \"POST\". Count the number of returned matches.",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["1"]  
        },
        {
            "quid": "e00ebec6",
            "question": "Look for any credentials within the payloads of any HTTP packets, what is the <b>password</b> you uncover?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "This is a more involved task that requires printing the individual HTTP packets (<code>-A</code>). From this, search for any relevant keywords like usernames or passwords.",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["ilovecats9102"]  
        },
        {
            "quid": "124a7545",
            "question": "Aside from HTTP on port 80, what is the other <b>well-known tcp port</p> in the capture?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "Use various command-line utilities to extract the destination port numbers from these packets, count the occurrences of each unique port, and then sort the counts in descending order. <b>Tip:</b> Don't forget the <code>-n</code> option to skip port name resolution and focus on the port numbers. Remember, this is asking for well-known ports, not ephemeral ports.",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["21", "ftp", "file transfer protocol"]  
        },
        {
            "quid": "7346acb0",
            "question": "What set of valid credentials did the endpoint use to access the file sharing server? <i>(Format username:password)</i>",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "The file transfer protocol takes in a <b>USER</b> and a <b>PASS</b> command as authentication.",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["demo:password", "demo password"]  
        },
        {
            "quid": "b254ed92",
            "question": "What is the name of the file that was <b>retrieved</b> from the file sharing server?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["readme.txt", "readme"]  
        },
        {
            "quid": "f8a131f8",
            "question": "Based on the unique <b>User-Agent</b> string found within the HTTP requests, what is the name of the related malware the endpoint might be infected with?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "This is a more involved task that requires printing the individual HTTP packets (<code>-A</code>). From this, search for the relevant HTTP header name and print the unique results. Perform OSINT on the abnormal looking string (Google).",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["lumma", "lummac2", "lumma c2", "lumma stealer", "lummac2 stealer", "Lumma Info-Stealer", "Lumma Info Stealer"]  
        },
        {
            "quid": "d2a3c10e",
            "question": "In <b>defanged format</b>, what was the full URL that the endpoint tried to connect to using the user agent identified above?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "Search through the printed packets for the User-Agent string identified in the previous question. Open up more lines of the packet (<code>grep -A</code>) and identify an HTTP header that indicates a redirect URL.",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["hxxps[://]t[.]me/+zz0192lskaaa"]  
        },
        {
            "quid": "dc406147",
            "question": "<b>[Bonus]</b> - What is the full title of the YouTube video that the user requested?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "hint": "Remember the <code>Location</code> HTTP header? Also, sorry in advance. ðŸ˜‚",
            "correct_answers": ["Rick Astley - Never Gonna Give You Up (Official Music Video)", "Rick Astley - Never Gonna Give You Up", "Never Gonna Give You Up", "rick roll"]
        }
    ]
  }